hi everyone this is prasad parthiban
today i'm going to take a training on
cyber risk insurance
what is a cyber risk
it is nothing but a potential harm or
loss that happens to an organization
due to the use of technology
let's take an example
see if i have a company to run my
company i need to use computers or
servers
for some reason
people like hackers if they try to
access my computer and try to put some
kind of virus that stops my business
this is one kind of cyber risk
so to avoid or to mitigate this problem
we need some kind of insurance so that
is why we use cyber insurance
now
you may have a question why can't
traditional insurance
cover this cyber
exposures for those who are new to
exposures loss exposures are nothing but
a potential
you know
exposure to a loss say if you have a
homeowners your building is a loss
exposure because your building can be
impacted by
fire or rain so anything that is exposed
to loss is called as loss exposure in
this case like for cyber insurance like
computer or server or data that got
exposed to these hackers they are called
as loss exposures
now there are two kinds of coverages
similar to all other policies like one
is first party coverages
second one is third party first part is
nothing but property and the
third party is nothing but liability
coverages
so if you see here okay before talking
about this cyber insurance i was about
to talk about traditional insurance
right so why do you need cyber insurance
like when you have traditional insurance
like you know general liability when
your traditional insurance like bpp
building and personal property why do
you need an exclusive cyber risk
insurance
if you take traditional insurance and
look at the coverages they cover very
very very minimal amount of coverage to
the cyber risk sometimes they don't even
cover so that's the reason why they have
an exclusive policy for covering cyber
risk insurance for an example
if you have a
company where you use a computer some
other no technological items the
traditional insurance could say that if
something happens say if your data got
breached if somebody access your data
and then they stole it now if your
customer
files a case against you the traditional
policies will have very certain limit
like ten thousand or twenty thousand
which may not be sufficient to address
your loss exposures so that is the
reason why it is very much advisable
that you don't rely on traditional
insurance and go to cyber risk insurance
now let's talk about different coverages
that we have at a high level
regarding cyber risk insurance
to start with first party which is
nothing but property
the first one is restoring lost income
and assuming operations say you have a
business
and for some reason
hackers hackers are nothing but
a specific kind of people who write
computer programs to access the
organization data or their computers or
decode the organization password and
then try to access their computers store
the data or like you know make sure
their computers are getting corrected so
all those activities are taken care by
this hackers so when they do that when
you have specific cyber risk insurance
you can make sure that if for some
reason
the hacker tries to ask your computer
and as a result you cannot run your
business for three months so this
coverage will make sure that it gives
required coverage during the three
months
so there are two categories that you can
talk about right one say if you have a
retail business you are allowing an
online website to run your business for
some reason your online website is act
now you cannot run your business right
similarly that's a direct exposure so
the way indirect exposure works is say
you have an online business
and
you are using a third party payment
services right in those cases if your
third party payment services is down due
to cyber attack still you cannot allow
the customers to make online payment so
that means you have some kind of
liability to your customers so those
kind of scenarios can be covered under
restoring lost income
bridge response right say you have
customer data day to day if i'm running
my company i can have customer data like
ssn
or their private information sellers and
everything for some reason if this
hackers try to hack that data then it's
very important as a company i have to
provide response to my clients so if i
do not provide my response on time or if
i do not provide at all then we could
get into problem right so that kind of
scenarios can be taken care by this
coverage breach response how do you
respond to a breach do you want to hire
an expert who can guide you on the next
steps or the expert can say what is in
what is that you have to do to overcome
this problem so those kind of scenarios
can be taken care by bridge response
computer crime similar to crime coverage
say if you have an employee who is part
of an organization he tries to know get
into your computer and then say like you
know try to transfer funds from your
organization to his own account so that
comes under computer crime so few of the
coverages that can be more trying to
give some examples so that you get a
feel of what is cyber risk insurance
coming to third party coverages right
like you know data and network liability
as i told you
the core thing is for any company to
have data can be customer data it can be
supplier data it can be company data so
for some reason if the hackers try to
hack the data
it comes in reliability where customers
can sue you so in those cases these
coverages can be used
regulatory defense like sometimes it's
very important that if something happens
to you that the customer data you ask
for the regulatory body you need to
respond to the customer within certain
time if you fail to do that then this
regulatory coverages can be used for
your defense mechanism
card sometimes what happens
if the customer is using their
credit card to make their payments
sometimes if that
details are getting breached by the
hackers then you can use this liability
coverage to take care of that
media liability sometimes you put some
information about some organizations in
your website or something else which you
got sued and you use this media
liability
and again
all these coverages are applicable when
it comes to cyber risk
now cyber risk as i told you it's not
kind of a traditional policy by itself
it's unique so it always comes with some
kind of challenges right so what kind of
challenges
breach of infrastructure
one thing the risk management people has
to be very careful is
the goal of cyber risk people is to make
a huge impact when it's a huge impact
they are going to try to access the
infrastructure like
say if i have a oil pump which gives
soil to the
thousands of companies they try to
access that and try to stop it so we
have to be very careful how to address
those medications
state-sponsored nowadays we know
if i a particular country have to fight
with another country
no more like a war they can do a cyber
attack and then access their system so
we have to be very cautious in those
scenarios so that's what state sponsored
cyber attacks
cloud outages we know most of the
companies are moving towards cloud so
the hackers are very much particular to
hack this cloud vendor so that if it
happens
it's not one company it's like thousands
of companies are going to have outage so
the cloud cloud providers are very much
specifically taking care or know very
much cautious about this cyber attackers
and they have required cyber risk
insurance
theft of ip that is intellectual
property which means
if you have a company you could have a
company essence when means you you
develop a new product you have the
formula for that so in those cases it is
very important that you take care of
that and we don't want the cyber
attacker to access that and then give it
to your competitor or someone else
social engineering schemes you as i told
you nowadays like you know people get a
lot of emails or no
advertisements saying that if you enroll
in this website we give you some kind of
offers so this is also prone to a lot of
cyber attacks
so this is what pretty much i wanted to
cover basically it's very important that
every company even it can be a small
company or big company they are prone
for cyber attacks and if it happens the
outcome is going to be very high so it's
very important you work with your
brokers or insurance company to evaluate
your current exposures and based on your
exposures get the required cyber risk
insurance
i hope you like my training video if you
like my training video please do
subscribe to my youtube channel have a
great day bye